wallstreetprep.com 2019-06-19

# Wall Street Prep Privacy Policy | Wall Street Prep - Wall Street Prep

_This Privacy Policy was last updated on June 1, 2018. In this update,  we have not made any material changes to the way we process data about our users, but we have updated our policy to make it easier to read and to comply with the EU General Data Protection Regulation.  **Related** : Terms of Use | Data Security Statement_

We at Wall Street Prep, LLC ( **“Wall Street Prep”** ,  **“we”** ,  **“us”** ) respect your privacy and want you to understand how we collect, use, and share data about you. This Privacy Policy covers our data collection practices and describes your rights to access, correct, or restrict our use of your personal data.

Unless we link to a different policy or state otherwise, this Privacy Policy applies when you visit or use the Wall Street Prep website or related services (the  **“Services”** ).

**By using the Services, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy.**  You should not use the Services if you don’t agree with this Privacy Policy or any other agreement that governs your use of the Services.

## 1\. Data Protection Officer and Data Security

In accordance with the General Data Protection Regulation, Wall Street Prep has appointed a data protection officer to oversee Wall Street Prep's data privacy policies and ensure your data rights including your right to access and right to erasure. For questions regarding this Privacy Policy or to exercise your data rights, you may contact Wall Street Prep’s data protection officer by email at [dpo@wallstreetprep.com](mailto:dpo@wallstreetprep.com). For more information on Wall Street Prep data security, visit our Data Security Statement.

## 2\. What Data We Get

We collect certain data from you directly, like information you enter yourself and data about your participation in courses and exams. We also collect some data automatically, like information about your device and location and what parts of our Services you interact with or spend time using.

### 2.1 Data You Provide to Us

We may collect different data from you/about you depending on how you use the Services. Below are some examples to help you better understand the data we collect.

When you create an account and use the Services, we collect any data you provide directly, including:

**Account Data** | In order to use certain features (like an online course), you need to create a user account. When you create or update your account, we collect and store the data you provide, like your email address and password. In addition, we assign you a unique identifying number (User ID).  
---|---  
**Course Data** | When you enroll in and take courses, we collect certain data including which courses, quizzes and exams you’ve started and completed as well as your exchanges with Wall Street Prep instructors and other users/students.  
**Payment Data** | If you make purchases, we collect certain data about your purchase (such as your name and zip code) as necessary to process your order. You must provide certain payment and billing data directly to our payment processing partners, including your name, credit card information, billing address, and zip code. For security, Wall Street Prep does not collect or store cardholder data, such as full credit card numbers or card authentication data.  
**Comments and Questions to Instructors** | You may contact Wall Street Prep instructors and interact with other users through our website commenting system, titled "Ask a Question" on online course pages and "Leave a Comment" on blog posts and articles. We collect and store the information you enter such as name, email address and question/comment content. We use this data to respond to you and research your question or concern, in accordance with this Privacy Policy. In addition, the first name and comment content will be posted and made available to the public/other website users. We will comply within 3 business days to any request to delete comment and question data completely from our systems.  
**Product reviews and Promotions** | We may invite you to complete a product/services review or participate in a promotion either through the Services or a third-party platform. If you participate, we will collect and store the data you provide as part of participating, such as your name and email address. That data is subject to this Privacy Policy unless otherwise stated in the official rules of the promotion or in another privacy policy. The data collected will be used to administer the promotion to you. Name and email data collected will not be posted on any publicly accessible page.  
**Technical and Services Support** | If you contact us for support or to report a problem or concern (regardless of whether you have created an account), we collect and store your contact information, messages, and other data about you like your name, email address, location, operating system, IP address, and any other data you provide or that we collect through automated means (which we cover below). We use this data to respond to you and research your question or concern, in accordance with this Privacy Policy.  
  
The data listed above is stored by us and is associated with your account.

### 2.2 Data We Collect through Automated Means

When you access the Services (including browsing courses), we collect certain data by automated means, including:

**System Data** | Technical data about your computer or device, like your IP address, device type, operating system type and version, unique device identifiers, browser, browser language, domain and other systems data, and platform types ( **“System Data”** ).  
---|---  
**Usage Data** | Usage statistics about your interactions with the Services, including courses accessed, time spent on pages or the Service, pages visited, features used, your search queries, click data, date and time, and other data regarding your use of the Services ( **“Usage Data”** ).  
**Approximate Geographic Data** | An approximate geographic location, including information like country, city, and geographic coordinates, calculated based on your IP address.  
  
The data listed above is collected through the use of server log files and tracking technologies, as detailed in the “Cookies and Data Collection Tools” section below. It is stored by us and associated with your account.

## 3\. How We Get Data About You

We use tools like cookies, email marketing services and analytics services to gather the data listed above. Some of these tools offer you the ability to opt out of data collection.

### 3.1 Cookies and Data Collection Tools

As detailed below in our Cookie Policy, Wall Street Prep and service providers acting on our behalf (like Google Analytics and third party applications) use server log files and automated data collection tools like cookies, tags, scripts, customized links, device or browser fingerprints, and web beacons (together,  **“Data Collection Tools”** ) when you access and use the Services. These Data Collection Tools automatically track and collect certain System Data and Usage Data (as detailed in Section 1) when you use the Services. In some cases, we tie data gathered through those Data Collection Tools to other data that we collect as described in this Privacy Policy.

We use cookies (small files that websites send to your device to uniquely identify your browser or device or to store data in your browser) for things like analyzing your use of the Services, personalizing your experience, making it easier to log into the Services, and recognizing you when you return. We or our third-party applications use web beacons (small objects that allow us to measure the actions of visitors and users using the Services) for things like identifying whether a page was visited, identifying whether an email was opened, and advertising more efficiently by excluding current users from certain promotional messages or identifying the source of a new mobile app download.

Wall Street Prep uses the following types of cookies:

  * _Preferences:_  cookies that remember data about your browser and preferred settings that affect the appearance and behavior of the Services (like your preferred language).
  * _Security:_  cookies used to enable you to log in and access the Services; protect against fraudulent logins; and help detect and prevent abuse or unauthorized use of your account.
  * _Functional:_  cookies that store functional settings (like the layout you've selected for viewing lessons or current promotions available to you).
  * _Session State:_  cookies that track your interactions with the Services to help us improve the Services and your browsing experience, remember your login details, and enable processing of your course purchases. These are strictly necessary for the Services to work properly.

You can set your web browser to alert you about attempts to place cookies on your computer, limit the types of cookies you allow, or refuse cookies altogether. If you do, you may not be able to use some or all features of the Services, and your experience may be less functional.

### 3.2 Analytics

We use third-party browser and mobile analytics services like Google Analytics. These services use Data Collection Tools to help us analyze your use of the Services, including information like the third-party website you arrive from, how often you visit, events within the Services and usage and performance data. We use this data to improve the Services, better understand how the Services perform on different devices, and provide information that may be of interest to you.

### 3.3 Online Advertising

We use third-party advertising services like Google’s ad services to deliver advertising about our Services on other websites and applications you use. The ads may be based on things we know about you, like your Usage Data and System Data (as detailed in Section 1), and things that these ad service providers know about you based on their tracking data. The ads can be based on your recent activity or activity over time and across other sites and services, and may be tailored to your interests.

Depending on the types of advertising services we use, they may place cookies or other tracking technologies on your device to collect data about your use of our Services, and may access those tracking technologies in order to serve these tailored advertisements to you. To help deliver tailored advertising, we may provide these service providers with a hashed, anonymized version of your email address (in a non-human-readable form) and content that you share publicly on the Services.

## 4\. What We Use Your Data For

We use your data to do things like provide our Services, communicate with you, troubleshoot issues, secure against fraud and abuse, improve and update our Services, analyze how people use our Services, serve personalized advertising, and as required by law or necessary for safety and integrity.

We use the data we collect through your use of the Services to:

  * Provide and administer the Services, including to display customized content and facilitate communication with other users;
  * Process your requests and orders for courses, products, specific services, information, or features;
  * Communicate with you about your account;
  * Manage your account preferences;
  * Facilitate the Services’ technical functioning, including troubleshooting and resolving issues, securing the Services, and preventing fraud and abuse;
  * Solicit feedback from users;
  * Market and administer reviews and promotions administered or sponsored by Wall Street Prep;
  * Learn more about you by linking your data with additional data through third-party data providers or analyzing the data with the help of analytics service providers;
  * Improve our Services and develop new products, services, and features;
  * Analyze trends and traffic, track purchases, and track usage data;
  * As required or permitted by law; or
  * As we, in our sole discretion, otherwise determine to be necessary to ensure the safety or integrity of our users, employees, third parties, the public, or our Services.

## 

We share certain data about you with training group leaders/instructors, administrators of organizations you are a member of, your employer, analytics and data enrichment providers, companies helping us run promotions or reviews/surveys, and advertising companies who help us promote our Services. We may also share your data as needed for security, legal compliance, or as part of a corporate restructuring. Lastly, we can share data in other ways if it is aggregated or de-identified or if we get your explicit consent.

We may share your data with third parties under the following circumstances or as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy:

  * **With Your Employer or Training Group Administrator:**  As many employers and university instructors or organizations use Wall Street Prep for coursework and training, we share your course, quiz and exam data including course completion and exam/quiz scores with employers/training group administrators/instructors who have signed you up for a Wall Street Prep account through a Service Agreement.
  * **With Service Providers, Contractors, and Agents:**  We share your data with third-party companies who perform services on our behalf, like payment processing, data analysis, marketing services, email and hosting services, and customer services and support. These service providers may access your personal data and are required to use it solely as we direct, to provide our requested service.
  * **With Analytics and Data Enrichment Services:**  As part of our use of third-party analytics tools like Google Analytics, we share certain contact information, Account Data, System Data, Usage Data (as detailed in Section 1), or de-identified data as needed. De-identified data means data for which we’ve removed things like your name and email address and replaced it with a token ID. This allows these providers to provide analytics services or match your data with publicly-available database information (including contact and social information from other sources). We do this to communicate with you in a more effective and customized manner.
  * **To Power Social Media Features:  **The social media features in the Services (like the Facebook Like button) may allow the third-party social media provider to collect things like your IP address and which page of the Services you’re visiting, and to set a cookie to enable the feature. Your interactions with these features are governed by the third-party company’s privacy policy.
  * **To Administer Reviews and Surveys:  **We may share your data as necessary to administer, market, or sponsor promotions and solicit reviews of products you choose to participate in, as required by applicable law (like to provide a winners list or make required filings), or in accordance with the rules of the promotion or survey.
  * **For Advertising:**  If we decide to offer advertising in the future, we may use and share certain System Data and Usage Data with third-party advertisers and networks to show general demographic and preference information among our users. We may also allow advertisers to collect System Data through Data Collection Tools (as detailed in Section 2.1), and to use this data to offer you targeted ad delivery to personalize your user experience (through behavioral advertising) and undertake web analytics. Advertisers may also share with us the data they collect about you. To learn more or opt out from participating ad networks’ behavioral advertising, see Section 6.1 (Your Choices About the Use of Your Data) below. Note that if you opt out, you’ll continue to be served generic ads.
  * **For Security and Legal Compliance:  **We may disclose your data to third parties if we (in our sole discretion) have a good faith belief that the disclosure is: 
    * Permitted or required by law;
    * Requested as part of a judicial, governmental, or legal inquiry, order, or proceeding;
    * Reasonably necessary as part of a valid subpoena, warrant, or other legally-valid request;
    * Reasonably necessary to enforce our Terms of Use, Privacy Policy, and other legal agreements;
    * Required to detect, prevent, or address fraud, abuse, misuse, potential violations of law (or rule or regulation), or security or technical issues; or
    * Reasonably necessary in our discretion to protect against imminent harm to the rights, property, or safety of Wall Street Prep, our users, employees, members of the public, or our Services.
    * We may also disclose data about you to our auditors and legal advisors in order to assess our disclosure obligations and rights under this Privacy Policy.
  * **During a Change in Control:  **If Wall Street Prep undergoes a business transaction like a merger, acquisition, corporate divestiture, or dissolution (including bankruptcy), or a sale of all or some of its assets, we may share, disclose, or transfer all of your data to the successor organization during such transition or in contemplation of a transition (including during due diligence).
  * **After Aggregation/De-identification:**  we can disclose or use aggregate or de-identified data for any purpose.
  * **With Your Permission:**  with your consent, we may share data to third parties outside the scope of this Privacy Policy.

## 6\. Security

We use appropriate security based on the type and sensitivity of data being stored. As with any internet-enabled system, there is always a risk of unauthorized access, so it’s important to contact us if you suspect any unauthorized access to your account.

Wall Street Prep takes appropriate security measures to protect against unauthorized access, alteration, disclosure, or destruction of your personal data that we collect and store. These measures vary based on the type and sensitivity of the data. Unfortunately, however, no system can be 100% secured, so we cannot guarantee that communications between you and Wall Street Prep, the Services, or any information provided to us in connection with the data we collect through the Services will be free from unauthorized access by third parties. Your password is an important part of our security system, and it is your responsibility to protect it. If you believe account has been compromised, you should  contact [dpo@wallstreetprep.com](mailto:dpo@wallstreetprep.com) with any concerns.

For more, visit our Data Security Statement.

## 7\. Your Rights

You have certain rights around the use of your data, including the ability to opt out of promotional emails, cookies, and collection of your data by certain analytics providers. You can update or terminate your account from within our Services, and can also contact us for individual rights requests about your personal data.

### 7.1 Your Choices About the Use of Your Data

You can choose not to provide certain data to us, but you may not be able to use certain features of the Services.

  * To stop receiving promotional communications from us, you can opt out by using the unsubscribe mechanism in the promotional communication you receive. Note that regardless of your email preference settings, we will send you transactional and relationship messages regarding the Services, including administrative confirmations, order confirmations, important updates about the Services, and notices about our policies.
  * The browser or device you use may allow you to control cookies and other types of local data storage. Your wireless device may also allow you to control whether location or other data is collected and shared.
  * To get information and control cookies used for tailored advertising from participating companies, see the consumer opt-out pages for the [Network Advertising Initiative](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices) and [Digital Advertising Alliance](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/), or if you’re located in the European Union, visit the [Your Online Choices](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/) site. To opt out of Google’s display advertising or customize Google Display Network ads, visit the [Google Ads Settings page](https://www.google.com/settings/ads).
  * To opt out of allowing Google Analytic to use your data for analytics or enrichment, see the [Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

If you have any questions about your data, our use of it, or your rights, contact us at [dpo@wallstreetprep.com](mailto:dpo@wallstreetprep.com).

### 7.2 Accessing, Updating, and Deleting Your Personal Data

You can access and update your personal data that Wall Street Prep collects and maintains as follows:

  * To update data you provide directly, log into your account and update your account at any time.
  * To terminate your account: 
    * If a Wall Street Prep account has been set up for you by an employer, training administrator, academic organization or other organization, you must request account termination through that organization.
    * If you signed up to Wall Street Prep yourself through a form or a purchase, email us at [dpo@wallstreetprep.com](mailto:dpo@wallstreetprep.com) for account termination.
    * Please note: even after your account is terminated, some or all of your data may still be visible to others, including without limitation any data that has been (a) copied, stored, or disseminated by other users (including in course comment); (b) shared or disseminated by you or others (including in your shared content); or (c) posted to a third-party platform. Even after your account is terminated, we retain your data for as long as we have a legitimate purpose to do so (and in accordance with applicable law), including to assist with legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. We may retain and disclose such data pursuant to this Privacy Policy after your account has been terminated.
  * To request to access, correct, or delete your personal data, email [dpo@wallstreetprep.com](mailto:dpo@wallstreetprep.com). Please allow up to 5 business days for a response. For your protection, we may require that the request be sent through the email address associated with your account, and we may need to verify your identity before implementing your request. Please note that we retain certain data where we have a lawful basis to do so, including for mandatory record-keeping and to complete transactions.

### 7.3 Our Policy Concerning Children

We recognize the privacy interests of children and encourage parents and guardians to take an active role in their children’s online activities and interests. Children under 13 (or under 16 in the European Economic Area) should not use the Services. If we learn that we’ve collected personal data from a child under those ages, we will take reasonable steps to delete it. Parents who believe that Wall Street Prep may have collected personal data from a child under those ages can submit a request that it be removed to [dpo@wallstreetprep.com](mailto:dpo@wallstreetprep.com).

## 8\. Jurisdiction-Specific Rules

If you live in California, you have certain rights to request information. Users outside of the United States should note that we transfer data to the US and other areas outside of the European Economic Area.

### 8.1 Users Outside of the U.S.

Wall Street Prep, Inc. is headquartered in Massachusetts, and in order to provide the Services to you we must transfer your data to the United States and process it there. By visiting or using our Services, you consent to storage of your data on servers located in the United States. If you are using the Services from outside the United States, you consent to the transfer, storage, and processing of your data in and to the United States or other countries. Specifically, personal data collected in Switzerland and the European Economic Area (“EEA”) is transferred and stored outside those areas.

That data is also processed outside of Switzerland and the EEA by our Wall Street Prep group companies, or our service providers, including to process transactions, facilitate payments, and provide support services as described in Section 4. We have entered into data processing agreements with our service providers that restrict and regulate their processing of your data on our behalf. By submitting your data or using our Services, you consent to this transfer, storage, and processing by Wall Street Prep and its processors.

## 9\. Updates & Contact Info

### 9.1 Modifications to This Privacy Policy

From time to time, we may update this Privacy Policy. If we make any material change to it, we will notify you via email, through a notification posted on the Services, or as required by applicable law. We will also include a summary of the key changes. Unless stated otherwise, modifications will become effective on the day they are posted.

As permitted by applicable law, if you continue to use the Services after the effective date of any change, then your access and/or use will be deemed an acceptance of (and agreement to follow and be bound by) the revised Privacy Policy. The revised Privacy Policy supersedes all previous Privacy Policies.

### 9.2 Interpretation

Any capitalized terms not defined in this policy are defined as specified in Wall Street Prep's Terms of Use.

### 9.3 Questions

If you have any questions, concerns, or disputes regarding our Privacy Policy, please feel free to contact our privacy team (including our designated data protection offiecr) at [dpo@wallstreetprep.com](mailto:dpo@wallstreetprep.com).

## Cookie Policy

_This Cookie Policy was last updated on June 1, 2018_

### What are cookies?

Cookies are small text files stored by your browser as you browse the internet. They can be used to collect, store, and share data about your activities across websites, including on Wall Street Prep. Cookies also allow us to remember things about your visits to Wall Street Prep, like your preferred language, and to make the site easier to use.

We use both session cookies, which expire after a short time or when you close your browser, and persistent cookies, which remain stored in your browser for a set period of time. We use session cookies to identify you during a single browsing session, like when you log into Wall Street Prep. We use persistent cookies where we need to identify you over a longer period, like when you request that we keep you signed in.

### Why does Wall Street Prep use cookies and similar technologies?

We use cookies and similar technologies like web beacons, pixel tags, or local shared objects (“flash cookies”), to deliver, measure, and improve our services in various ways. We use these cookies both when you visit our site and services through a browser and through our mobile app. As we adopt additional technologies, we may also gather additional data through other methods.

We use cookies for the following purposes:

**Authentication and security** | 

  * To log you into Wall Street Prep
  * To protect your security
  * To help detect and fight spam, abuse, and other activities that violate Wall Street Prep’s agreements

---|---  
  
For example, cookies help authenticate your access to Wall Street Prep and prevent unauthorized parties from accessing your accounts.

**Preferences** | 

  * To remember data about your browser and your preferences
  * To remember your settings and other choices you’ve made

---|---  
  
For example, cookies help us remember your preferred language or the country you’re in, so we can provide content in your preferred language without asking each time you visit.

**Analytics and research** | 

  * To help us improve and understand how people use Wall Street Prep

---|---  
  
For example, cookies help us test different versions of Wall Street Prep to see which features or content users prefer, web beacons help us determine which email messages are opened, and cookies help us see how you interact with Wall Street Prep, like the links you click on.

We also work with a number of analytics partners, including Google Analytics, who use cookies and similar technologies to help us analyze how users use the Services, including by noting the sites from which you arrive. Those service providers may either collect that data themselves or we may disclose it to them.

You can opt out of some of these services through tools like the [Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on.](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout)

**Personalized content** | 

  * To customize Wall Street Prep with more relevant content

---|---  
  
For example, cookies help us show a personalized list of recommended courses on the homepage.

**Advertising** | 

  * To provide you with more relevant advertising

---|---  
  
To learn more about targeting and advertising cookies and how you can opt out, visit [www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies/index.html](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies/index.html), or if you’re located in the European Union, visit the [Your Online Choices site](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/).

Please note that where advertising technology is integrated into the Services, you may still receive advertising on other websites and applications, but it will not be tailored to your interests.

### What are my privacy options?

You have a number of options to control or limit how we and our partners use cookies:

  * Most browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can change your browser settings to decline cookies by consulting your browser’s support articles. If you decide to decline cookies, please note that you may not be able to sign in, customize, or use some interactive features in the Services.
  * Flash cookies operate differently than browser cookies, so your browser’s cookie-management tools may not remove them. To learn more about how to manage Flash cookies, see Adobe’s [article on managing flash cookies](https://helpx.adobe.com/flash-player/kb/disable-local-shared-objects-flash.html) and [Website Storage Settings panel](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html).
  * To get information and control cookies used for tailored advertising from participating companies, see the consumer opt-out pages for the [Network Advertising Initiative](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices) and [Digital Advertising Alliance](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/), or if you’re located in the European Union, visit the [Your Online Choices site](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/). To opt out of Google Analytics’ display advertising or customize Google Display Network ads, visit the [Google Ads Settings page](https://www.google.com/settings/ads).
  * For general information about targeting cookies and how to disable them, visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

### Updates & Contact Info

From time to time, we may update this Cookie Policy. If we do, we’ll notify you by posting the policy on our site with a new effective date. If we make any material changes, we’ll take reasonable steps to notify you in advance of the planned change.
